A Guide to the Virginia Documents, 1770-1913
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Virginia Documents 1770-1913
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-457
16 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content
Includes appointment, 25 October 1770, of James Lane as sheriff of Loudoun County, Va., signed by William Nelson; appointment, 27 November 1783, of Joseph Lane, William Gunnell, William Fitzhugh and Thomas Kennon as justices of the peace for Loudoun County, Va., also assigning them special powers to hear criminal cases involving slaves, signed by Benjamin Harrison; and order, 2 January 1778, to George Rogers Clark to raise a force to attack a British post at Kaskaskia, Ill., signed by Patrick Henry.
Also includes commission to James McClung, 1797 September 20, signed by James Wood; commission to Charles Seacat, 1802 October 18, signed by James Monroe; commission, 1803 September 13 to Alexander Paxton signed by John Page; commission, 1805 September 12, to William Houston, signed by John Guerrant; commission, 1809 June 29, to Samuel Carrick signed by George William Smith; commission, 1814 February 21, to Andrew Wallace, signed by James Barbour; commission, 1816 February 14, to James Adams signed by Wilson Cary Nicholas; commission, 1822 June 13, to Samuel Wilson, signed by Thomas Mann Randolph; commission,1823 May 15, to Addison Gilmore, signed by james Pleasants, Jr.; appointment, 11 December 1844, of William Massie as sheriff of Nelson County, Va., signed by James McDowell; and commissions, 1787-1830, for officers in the Virginia Militia, predominantly from Rockbridge County, Va., including commissions for James McClung and William MacKay. Commission signers include James Barbour, John Floyd, James Monroe, Wilson Cary Nicholas, John Page, James Pleasants, Thomas M. Randolph, and James Wood.
Contents List
- Nelson, William 1770 Oct 25
  Commission issued to James Lane as sheriff of Loudon County
- Orders to Lieutenant Colonel George Rogers Clark to raise 350 men for an attack on the British post at Kaskaskia; signed by Patrick Henry (facsimile) 1778 Jan 2
- Harrison, Benjamin 1783 Nov 27
  Commission issued to Joseph Lane, William Gunnell, William Fitzhugh, and Thomas Kennon as justices of the peace for Loudon County
- Wood, James 1797 Sep 20
  Commission issued to James McClung as captain, 1st battalion, 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 3rd division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Monroe, James 1802 Oct 18
  Commission issued to Charles Seacat as captain, 2nd battalion, 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 3rd division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Page, John 1803 Sep 13
  Commission issued to Alexander Paxton as ensign, 1st battalion, 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 3rd division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Guerrant, John 1805 Sep 12
  Commission issued to William Houston as lieutenant, 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 3rd division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Smith, George William 1809 Jun 29
  Commission issued to Samuel Carrick as lieutenant, 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 3rd division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Barbour, James 1814 Feb 21
  Commission issued to Andrew Wallace as lieutenant, 13th brigade, 3rd division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Nicholas, Wilson C. 1816 Feb 14
  Commission issued to James Adams as captain of 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 3rd division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Randolph, Thomas Mann 1822 Jun 13
  Commission issued to Samuel Wilson as ensign, 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 5th division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Pleasants, James Jr. 1823 May 15
  Commission issued to Addison Gilmore as ensign, 8th regiment, 13th brigade, 5th division of militia of Rockbridge County
- Floyd, John 1830 Jun 8
  Commission issued to Willia Mackay as cornet, cavalry troop, 5th regiment, 5th division, Virginia militia
- McDowell, James 1844 Dec 11
  Commission issued to William Massie as sheriff of Nelson County
- Mann, William Hodges 1912 Nov 25
  Certificate of electors for President and Vice-President of the United States
- Certificate of electors of the State of Virginia of votes for President of the United States, Woodrow Wilson, and Thomas R. Marshall, Vice-President 1913 Jan 13, 12 signatures